因此，我们将在 Docker 上运行 node.js ，因为我是一个节点开发者，并且
So we're gonna move on to node.js on
Docker because I'm a node developer and
我喜欢这样你就卡住了我有麦克风
that's what I like, and so
you're stuck cuz I have the microphone.
但我要教你的一切都很顺利
But pretty much everything that
I'm gonna teach you here, one,
你根本不需要知道这么多的节点
you don't really need
to know Node that much.
我要给你所有的密码并不一定要你理解
I'm gonna give you all of the code and not
necessarily expect you to understand it.
第二，这个可以应用于 Ruby，它可以应用到 Go，它可以是
And two, this could be applied to Ruby,
it could be applied to Go, it could be
应用于爪哇，钴，珍珠，我不知道，不管你喜欢什么
applied to Java, Cobalt, Pearl,
I don't know, whatever suits your fancy.
我不会感到羞耻
I'm not gonna shame.
但就为了开始进入其他类型的
But just to kind of start getting
into some of these other flavors of
可能对你有用的容器
containers that might be useful to you,
in particular,
因为我们每天都要用那个
the node one because we are gonna
be using that one all day.
所以我们现在就在 MacOS 模式
So we're here in MacOS mode right now.
我要说码头工人跑了
And I'm gonna say docker run dash it.
我要说的是
And I'm gonna say node,
这不是 Docker 认证为官方认证的官方节点容器。
which isn't the official node container
that Docker certifies as official.
这些都是由一个叫 NodeSource的公司建造的，
These are actually built by
a company called NodeSource,
做非常棒的节点咨询的人
wonderful people that do
really great node consulting.
它们制造了奇妙的容器
And they make wonderful containers,
他们是其中的专家所以我依赖他们而我自己也不这样做
they're experts in it, that's why I
rely on them and I don't do it myself.
然后在这里如果我做了节点这将会是最新的
And then here, if I did node,
this would run latest,
我想这和我现在要告诉你的一样
which I think would be the same as
what I'm gonna tell you to do now.
但我又想暂时冻结了对吧
But again,
I wanna kind of freeze in time, right?
就像你把你的附属品送到生产之前
Just like you pin your dependencies
before you send them in production,
所以我要给你一个正确的标签
that's why I'm gonna give
you the correct tag here.
所以我想运行节点 12，然后我希望它专门针对 Debian 拉伸。
So I wanna run node 12, and then I want it
to be tied specifically to Debian stretch.
所以我要说 12 个破折号
So I'm gonna say 12 dash stretch.
所以其实我就好像没有那个地方，所以
So actually, that looks like
I don't have that locally, so
它会把它拉出来的
it's actually gonna go out and pull that.
>> 您是否可以帮助我了解将节点绑定到 Debian 拉伸意味着什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Could you help me understand what do
you mean by tying node to Debian stretch?
>> 确定。
&gt;&gt; Sure.
因此，每当您运行 Docker 容器时，
So whenever you run a Docker container,
事情会有多多多多多多多数对吧
There's multiple versions of
things going to it, right?
我在这个特殊情况下用节点图像处理的事情
And the thing that I'm gonna care in this
particular case with the node image,
我在乎的两个东西就是我在乎的是什么
the two things that I really care about
the versions of is I care about what
Linux 的版本和我在乎的是哪个版本的节点，对吧 ?
version of Linux it's on and I care
what version of Node it's on, right?
12号节点 12号是有道理的
So the 12, that's node 12,
that makes sense.
Stretch 把它绑在 Debian的特定版本上
Stretch is tying it to
a specific version of Debian,
我相信是德比七
which I believe is Debian seven.
别引用我的话说我不太了解德比
Don't quote me on that,
cuz I don't really know Debian very well.
我们为什么要去 Debian 和 Ubuntu
Now, why are we doing
Debian versus Ubuntu?
这就是他们构建的节点图像，对吧 ?
That is just what they build
the Node images with, right?
我想你能在仿生和其他 Ubuntu的版本上找到它
I think you can get it on Bionic and
other versions of Ubuntu,
但缺省情况下是在 Debian
but by default it's on Debian.
> > 就好像这两个人一样
&gt;&gt; It is kind of like
a mash up on those two.
> > 嗯，实际上下一届会议实际上是关于标签，
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so actually literally the next
session I'll be talking about tags,
这就是现在的情况
which is what this is.
但可以说这是任意的
But suffice to say it's arbitrary.
因此，谁创建容器，就会选择要调用的标记。
So whoever creates the container
chooses what the tags are called.
所以他们可以叫它拉伸破折号 12
So they could have called
it stretch dash 12.
他们可以给它打个电话
They could have called it
whatever they wanted to.
有道理吗
That makes sense?
> > 是。 >> Cool。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Cool.
>> 那么拉伸只是一个名称没有吗 ?
&gt;&gt; So
stretch is just a name does not have any?
>> 很容易记住 Debian 的版本，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; It's a really easy way to remember
the version of Debian, right?
同样地，我还记不起 Debian 版本的数字是什么，
Again, like I can't remember what the
numbers of what Debian version we're on,
但我知道 Stretch 是最新的 LTS，就是
but I know that Stretch is the latest one,
latest LTS, that is.
有道理吗
Does that make sense?
> > 嗯，我只是不确定 Stretch 是最新的还是什么的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I just wasn't sure if Stretch
was a term for latest or something.
> > 它不，不，它是专门针对 Debian的。
&gt;&gt; It's not, no,
it's specifically for Debian.
就好像我们一直在用 Ubuntu Bionic ，对，就是 18.04，
It's like we've been using Ubuntu Bionic
this whole time, right, which is 18.04,
这就是史特奇对 Debian的事
that's what Stretch is for Debian.
>> 谢谢。 > > 是。
&gt;&gt; Thank you.
&gt;&gt; Yep.
所以我们有了另外两个层次它很快就会被下载到这里
So we got, looks like two more layers that
it's gonna download here very quickly.
>> 布莱恩，你也要我们下载这个图片吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian, do you want us to
download this image, too?
> 嗯，可能吧。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, probably.
是的，答案是肯定的，我们会在整个过程中使用几次
Yes, the answer's yes cuz we'll
use it several times throughout
其他的当然了
the rest of the course.
那就得把一切都提取了，然后重新申请一切，所以
Then, it has to go extract everything and
then reapply everything, so
它需要一点处理
it takes a bit of processing.
好了，我们下载了图像，它拉开了它并执行了它，
So okay, we downloaded the image,
it pulled it and executed it, and
现在它让我们变成了 REPL对吧
now it drops us into some sort of REPL,
right?
REPL 就像上帝， REPL 的立场是什么 ?
REPL being like a, god,
what does REPL stand for?
我相信这里有人知道
I'm sure someone here knows.
不管怎样它代表某种东西 R-E-P-L
Anyway, it stands for something, R-E-P-L.
我相信交谈中有 9 个人说这代表了这一点。
I'm sure there's nine people on
the chat saying it stands for this.
>> Read， Evalue， Print和 Loop。
&gt;&gt; Read, Evalue, Print, Loop.
>> 是，读，求值，打印，循环，在那里。
&gt;&gt; Yep, Read, Evaluate,
Print, Loop, there it is.
让我吃惊的是它是个 JavaScript对吧
And surprise, it's a JavaScript, right?
所以我可以说，控制台点日志 x是吧 ?
So I can say console dot log x, right?
它会做到这一点，或者 2 加 2，对吧 ?
And it'll do that, or
2 plus 2, whatever, right?
所以这把我们扔进了 Debian Stretch Linux 的节点 REPL ，对吧 ?
So this dropped us into the node REPL
inside of a Debian Stretch Linux, right?
这也许不是你期待的
Which may or
may not be what you're expecting.
但就像我说的，这个容器用来定义什么指令真正的运行。
But like I said, the container gets to
define what command actually gets run.
这就变成了一个 REPL ，它代表着读，执行，打印和循环，对吗 ?
So this drops up into a REPL, which stands
for read, execute, print, and loop, right?
对于节点 js。
For node js.
所以，如果我说点像控制台点日志 x，它会注销 x，对吗 ?
So if I just say something like console
dot log x, it's gonna log out x, right?
正常的 JavaScriptty 之类的对吧
Normal JavaScripty kinda stuff, right?
如果你只在你的电脑上写就写节点
If you just do it on your computer and
you just write node,
这就是它为你做的
this is what it does for you.
就像我之前跟你说过的容器自己决定
Like I was telling you before,
the containers themselves get to decide.
如果我不指定你可以在这里看到的命令
If I don't specify command,
which you can see up here, right there,
我没有具体说明是吧
I didn't specify a command, right?
所以不管它的缺省值是什么
So it does whatever it defaults to,
in this case, it's like I'm gonna
将您放入节点 REPL ，因为我不知道您实际想做什么，好吗 ?
put you into the node REPL because I've no
idea what you actually want to do, okay?
这就是这里所做的
So that's what this does here.
我看到出口了
I see the exit.
好了好了
There we go.
然后按 Ctrl +C 两次，这会让您退出 REPL。
So hit Ctrl+C twice,
that'll get you out of the REPL.
然后就在那个点完成货柜，对，
And then, it finishes
the container at that point, right,
因为那是它设计的 CMD
because that's the CMD that
it was designed to do.
但如果我真的想被扔进 Linux 的一部分
But if I actually wanna be dropped
into just the Linux part of it,
我可以说巴什对吧
I can say bash, right?
现在我在这个容器里
And now, I'm inside of this container.
但是和其他的一样，首先，如果我说猫猫问题，
But as opposed to the other ones,
first of all, if I say cat /etc/issue,
你可以看到我的样子好像是德宾 9 号的样子
you can see I'm on, looks like it's
Debin nine is what stretch is.
我错了我以为是 7
I was wrong, I thought it was seven.
任何案例都是我们的 Linux
Any case,
that's what kind of Linux we're in.
Ubuntu 是基于 Debian 的所以一切都会感觉很舒服
And Ubuntu is based on Debian,
so everything's gonna feel very,
非常熟悉
very familiar to you.
但是如果我说的是节点破折号对吧
But what's cool about this one
if I say node dash v, right,
现在它已安装节点，因为我得到了节点容器，好吗 ?
now it has Node installed because
I got the Node container, okay?
你可以看到这里，我有 Node 12 ，这正是我所要求的。
So you can see here, I have Node 12,
which is exactly what I asked for.
所以这很有趣，对吧 ?
So that's kind of fun, right?
所以我觉得我觉得也是很有用的，
So again,
something I think is quite useful, too,
就是知道这猫的事是吧
is just knowing this cat /etc/issue thing,
right?
如果你运行节点，对，我就像这样运行 Node ，
If you run Node, right, and
I just run Node like this,
我现在就不干了
which I'm not gonna do right now.
你可能不知道这是 Debian吧
You might not know that this is Debian,
right?
我不知道这是否错误的假设
I don't know if it's a faulty assumption,
but
我只是假设大多数事情都是 Ubuntu ，因为这就是我所使用的。
I just assume most things are Ubuntu
because that's what I use.
但在这个特殊情况下，他们决定去别的地方。
But in this particular case,
they decided to go with something else.
但这是一种很好的方式来表达，好，我在哪里，我在做什么，
But this is a good way to kinda say,
okay, where am I, what am I doing,
陆地上的土地是什么
what's the lay of the land there?
我们将进入您可以选择的 Linux 分发版。
We'll go into later which Linux
distributions you can select.
但我的意思是，故事的总和是选择你最喜欢的那个。
But I mean, the sum of the story is choose
the one that you're most comfortable with.
所有这些都很好。
All of these are really good.
Red Hat Linux 是一个很好的 Linux 。
Red Hat Linux is a good one.
薄荷，阿尔卑斯， Debian， Ubuntu，
Mint, Alpine, Debian, Ubuntu,
他们都是有效的选择取决于你想做什么
they're all valid choices just
depending what you wanna do.